Guide to the Edward J. Trethaway papers, 1936-2012
Trethaway, Edward J. papers, 1936-2012
- Contents
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 1 Section 5 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 1 Section 6 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 1 Section 7 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 1 Section 8 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 1 Section 9 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 1 Section 10, Part A (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 1 Section 10, Part B (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 1 Section 10, Part C (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 1 Epilogue (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 1 Index (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 1 Production - Mary's House (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Life and Times of Joseph Trethaway (Box 10)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 1 Rough Draft of "Life and Times" (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 2 Cover and Table of Contents (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 2 Section 1 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 2 Section 2 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 2 Section 3 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 2 Index (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 2 Rough Draft of "Delta Tau Delta" (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - "Efforts in Behalf of Beta Omicron Chapter of Delta Tau Delta Fraternity" Volume 2 by Edward Joseph Trethaway (Box 10)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 3 Cover and Table of Contents (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 3 Section 1 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 3 Section 2 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 3 Section 3 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 3 Section 4 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 3 Index (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - E.J. Trethaway Vol. 3 Rough Draft of "Cornell Employment" (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - "The Cornell Employment Years (1963-1982)" Volume 3 by Edward Joseph Trethaway (Box 11)
  - E.J. Trethaway Duplicate Exhibits: Vol. 1, Sections 1-3 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - E.J. Trethaway Duplicate Exhibits: Vol. 1, Sections 4-6 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - E.J. Trethaway Duplicate Exhibits: Vol. 1, Sections 7-9 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - E.J. Trethaway Duplicate Exhibits: Vol. 1, Section 10, Parts A-B (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - E.J. Trethaway Duplicate Exhibits: Vol. 1, Section 10, Part C (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - E.J. Trethaway Duplicate Exhibits: Vol. 1 Epilogue-end (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - E.J. Trethaway Duplicate Exhibits: Vol. 2 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - E.J. Trethaway Duplicate Exhibits: Vol. 3, Sections 1-2 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - E.J. Trethaway Duplicate Exhibits: Vol. 3, Sections 3-4 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Book Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Major Gift Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - The Trust Agreement by Edward J. Trethaway to Provide the Joseph D. Trethaway Fund (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Endowment Correspondence (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Diseker (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Heather/Roger Soener (Heather is Pat's Sister's Daughter) 1987- (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Doke Problem (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Dottie (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Ben Stambaugh (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Past Cornell Secretary (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Scott and Jo Ann (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Scott's Rollins College Costs, Divorce, Wedding (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Shirley Booth (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Hal Trethaway (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Schimoler, Louis (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Corson - Prior to Tretaway's Retirement (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Griswold - A Life-Long Friend (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - McJunkin - Python (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Barbara Covino (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Fred Kahn (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Ann Mansfield Lawrence (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Edwina Marchev (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Peter Mason (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - John Palmer (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - John D. Murray, D.V.M. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Dr. Edward C. Melby Jr. (Before Retirement) (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Dr. Edward C. Melby Jr. (After Trethaway Retired) (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Navy Memorial (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Ellis Island Wall of Honor; Sacagawea Dollar Coin; D-Day Memorial; World War II Memorial, etc. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Pond Boat (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Pipes and Pipe Tobacco (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Memos on Cape Cod (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Chatham Police Problems (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Chatham Police Problems (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Chatham Police Problems (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Re: Chatham Town (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Photograph Contests and Interesting Photos (Retirement Era) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Chicadees Hand Feeding in Retirement (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Prostate Cancer. Changes in Procedures Brought About by EJT (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Prostate Cancer. How to Deal With Advanced Prostate Cancer and Pain (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Prostate Cancer (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Prostate Cancer (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Prostate Cancer (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Althausen (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Sale of Chatham House to Heartleih - 2002 (Retirement Era) (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - American Heritage. Sale of the House (Retirement Era) (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Auction Houses (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Classic. The magazine About Horses. (December 1975) (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Zweig Fund (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Norris and Schraubstader (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Cornell Development Miscelaneous (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Jones' Grievance (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Ramin's Death 6/95. McJunkins out of Chimes Project (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Cornell Alumni (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Daily Sun Malott L to E Canine Symposium Progress. Dr. Law in Countryman (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Friends (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - World War II (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Songs (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Cornell Miscellaneous - 2 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Faulty #1 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Faculty #2 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Delta Tau Delta I (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Delta Tau Delta II (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Handi-Chair (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous Chatham (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Ithaca Items (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Whydah (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Letters After Mother and Dad's Deaths (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Cape Cod Hospital (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Rollings Baseball Trophy (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Art of Charity - 1994 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Trethaway Fund (Endowment) (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Very Miscellaneous I (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Cornell Lacrosse - 1949 EJT Manager (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Racker Centers. Berko Lectureship (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - City/Country Rules, Articles (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Burlington Police (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Burlington Police - 2 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Police Matters. Book (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - High Speed Chases. Press Releases. Copies. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Complimentary Letters (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Union Congregation Church (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Cornell Songs (Box 14)
  - English Rules and Usage (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Taxes 95, 96, 97 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Julie Harris (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Request for Funds from the Town of Chatham for the Fiscal Year 1987 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Lookout Hill (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Board of Visitors Material 1975-1976 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Dedication Ceremony (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Rockwell (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Seeing Eye - Correspondence (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Racker Centers (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Aluminum horseshoe found by Trethaway's father (Box 15)
  - Wood piece of Special molding (Box 15)
  - Delta-Tau-Delta souvenir (Box 15)
  - Utah beach sand (Box 15)
  - Loe Bar, Corwall beach sand (Box 15)
  - Brick from Marconi Station (Box 15)
  - A section of a spruce, planted in 1830 (Box 15)
  - A section of an old oak tree (Box 15)
  - An embosser for a Handychair (Box 15)
  - The last tree out from near Nelson line (Box 15)
  - Woden joints (Box 15)
  - Modified spark plug (Box 15)
  - A core sample from the 4th floor of Day Hall (Box 15)
  - Trethaway Father's slide rule (Box 15)
  - Trethaway's slide rule (Box 15)
  - A defective submarine cable (Box 15)
  - Cuff links (Box 15)
  - Football team pins, etc. (Box 15)
  - Presidential campaign badges (Box 15)
  - Cornell badges (Box 15)
  - Two quartz crystal units (Box 15)
  - Glass bottle (Play prop) (Box 15)
  - "Pleasant View" golf prize (Box 15)
  - Junior Essex Troop Spurs (Box 15)
  - A woodchuck tail (Box 15)
  - Drafting Instruments (Box 15)
  - Ruler-letter opener (Box 15)
  - The 100th Cornell reunion beer mug (Box 15)
  - Key chain float. "Free Spirit" boat (Box 15)
  - Bunker's collar (Box 15)
  - Trethaway name pin (Box 15)
  - Partial seal skull (Box 15)
  - 3 pencils, 1 pen (Box 15)
  - Military service insignia and pins (Box 15)
  - Miscellaneous pins (7th grade - military service) (Box 15)
  - The Studebaker Champion manual and maker's emblem (Box 15)
  - Victory ribbon (Box 15)
  - 29 GA quartz crystals from WE 1953 (Box 15)
  - EJT's extracted teeth (Box 15)
  - 24 Film negative rolls (Box 15)
  - Contact prints (Box 15)
  - Heather 8/4/06. TR 8729a(Audio Cassette) (Box 15)
  - Days After Dotties. TR 8730a(Audio Cassette) (Box 15)
  - Heather 1. TR 8731a (Audio Cassette) (Box 15)
  - Alex Anderson. A Hawaiian Heritage Classic. TR 8732a(Audio Cassette) (Box 15)
  - Prostate 2. TR 8733a (Audio Cassette) (Box 15)
  - Prostate 1. TR 8734a(Audio Cassette) (Box 15)
  - Chief Goudlin. TR 8735a (Audio Cassette from Folder 14-14) (Box 15)
  - Chapel Hill, Orlando. TR 8736a(Audio Cassette from Folder 14-14) (Box 15)
  - 25 - 35mm Slides from the Construction of Delata House (Box 15)
  - Woodport Camp. Campus Ranger Photograph (Box 15)
  - Two Boot Camp Photographs, 1945 (Box 15)
  - Contact prints, audio tapes (Box 15)
  - Photographs and a CD (Box 15)
  - Easter card to father (Box 15)
  - Fields and Opportunities in Engineeering (Essay) (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - The Georginnian (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - My Vacations (Essays) (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Letters (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, school report cards (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Photographs from 1976 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Platoon #3 Troop C photograph (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook 1937 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Photo Album 1939-1945 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Woodport Camp Accident, 1936 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - "The Life and Times of Edward Joseph Trethaway" Vol. 1 and 3 (RESTRICTED) (Box 17)
  - Correspondence between Ned Trethaway and RMC staff, 1992-2012 (RESTRICTED) (Box 18)
  - Jewelry (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Deane W. Malott, 1991-2000 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Ben Stambaugh (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Reed and Eleanor McJunkin (Box 19, Folder 4)
    Includes CD-1953 - Cornell Chimes, McJunkin Concert
  - Correspondence regarding autobiography, 1968-2009 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Veterinary medicine (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Group photo at Camp Rancer, 1937 (Folder 1)
  - S.S. Morro Castle photo, ashore at Asbury Park, NJ, Sept 9, 1934 (Folder 1)
  - Awards and Cornell diploma (Folder 1)